# Yuya **Tinnefeld**

Cloud DevOps Engineer

Phone: (+49) 1797908144

Email: yuyatinnefeld@gmail.com

Address: Düsseldorf

yuyatinnefeld.com

#### SKILLS

**Programming Languages** 

Python, Go, Shell, SQL

**Cloud Provider** 

GCP, AWS

#### DevOps

Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform, Gitlab, GitHub, ArgoCD, Prometheus, Grafana

#### Data Engineering / Big Data

PostgreSQL, MySQL, BigQuery, Snowflake, Spark, Hadoop, Airflow, InfluxDB, Kafka, MongoDB

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

Japanese (Native Language) German (Fluent, C2) English (Business, C1)

#### CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

HashiCorp Terraform HashiCorp Vault Prometheus

#### SUMMARY/OBJECTIVE

Passionate Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience in data engineering and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. I always loved the tickle of excitement that you get, when you jump heads on into a new project. While diving deeper into this versatile technology, it just amazes me over and over again.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cloud DevOps Engineer // REWE digital, Cologne

07/2021 - Todav

- CI/CD for Backend & Frontend Apps (Docker, k8s, Gitlab CI)
- IaC Integration (Terraform)
- Data Pipeline Development (Spark, Dataproc, Airflow)
- Application Development (FastAPI, Cloud Run, GCE)
- Service Migration from On-Premise on GCP
- Logging and Monitoring (GCP)

Marketing Data Analyst & Engineer // Publics Media, Düsseldorf 03/2018 - 06/2021

- Data Engineering (Flask, Pandas, Selenium)
- Data Analysis & Tracking (GA, BigQuery, Jupyter)
- Projekt Management, Workshops, Consulting

### Web Analyst & SEO // RTL Interactive, Cologne

09/2017 - 02/2018

- Web Analytics (Google Analytics)
- Search Engine Optimization (On- and Off Page)

## Student Trainee & Internship // network.publishing, Cologne

12/2016 - 08/2017

- Web Analytics (Google Analytics)
- Data Warehouse & Data Mining

#### ECommerce Startup CEO & CTO // Wanamour, Cologne

11/2014 - 06/2022

- Management
- Web Development & Web Design
- Marketing

#### **EDUCATION**

University of applied sciences Bonn-Rhein-Sieg

B.Sc. Business information systems

09/2013 - 08/2017

Focus area: Business Intelligence (Data-Warehouse, Data Mining, Predictive Analysis, Decision Support System